<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>distribits</title><link>https://distribits.live/</link><description>Recent content on distribits</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://distribits.live/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://distribits.live/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://distribits.live/about/</guid><description>Technologies for distributed data management April 18th - April 20th, 2024 at “Haus der Universität”, Düsseldorf, Germany Registration is closed. Thank you for shaping an exciting event with your contribution!
We are currently creating a schedule, and will send out acceptance emails by November 1st. If you’ve missed the deadline but wanted to participate, please stay tuned - we will be able to accommodate late registrations in a short while.</description></item><item><title>Location</title><link>https://distribits.live/location/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://distribits.live/location/</guid><description>Venue Haus der Universität Düsseldorf
Schadowplatz 14
40212 Düsseldorf
Located in downtown Düsseldorf (OpenStreetMap) Auditorium Two mergeable seminar rooms (hackathon venue) University network (eduroam) Transport 25 min by public transport from the airport (DUS) 16 min walk from the train station See directions at the venue website Accommodation You will find a large amount of very affordable accommodations within a 1-2km range of the location. We took care that the conference does not coincide with large events or fairs.</description></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>https://distribits.live/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://distribits.live/schedule/</guid><description>Registration opens: September 14th
Registration and submission closes: midnight October 22nd
Registration and submission feedback: by November 1st
Preliminary schedule: Conference Thursday, 18 April 2024, 9&amp;ndash;18 Friday, 19 April 2024, 9&amp;ndash;18 Hackathon Saturday, 20 April 2024, 9&amp;ndash;18</description></item><item><title>News</title><link>https://distribits.live/news/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://distribits.live/news/</guid><description>Registration is closed! Thanks for everyone&amp;rsquo;s registrations and contribution submissions! It looks like the first distribits meeting is going to be what we hoped for: An inspiring event for technology enthusiasts with many backgrounds. We received registrations from Europe, North America, and Asia, from people working on research data curation, climate science, imaging, archeology, data portals, archiving solutions, small and scale large.
We will now work on finalizing the schedule, and send out emails to everyone by November 1st.</description></item><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>https://distribits.live/code-of-conduct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://distribits.live/code-of-conduct/</guid><description>Our Pledge We as members, contributors, and leaders pledge to make participation in our community a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of age, body size, visible or invisible disability, ethnicity, sex characteristics, gender identity and expression, level of experience, education, socio-economic status, nationality, personal appearance, race, caste, color, religion, or sexual identity and orientation.
We pledge to act and interact in ways that contribute to an open, welcoming, diverse, inclusive, and healthy community.</description></item></channel></rss>