<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>distribits</title><link>https://distribits.live/</link><description>Recent content on distribits</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://distribits.live/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://distribits.live/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://distribits.live/about/</guid><description>Distribits: technologies for distributed data management April 4th - April 6th, 2024 at “Haus der Universität”, Düsseldorf, Germany The first distribits meeting will happen in 2024, and we are inviting all interested parties to join! The aim of this meeting is to bring together enthusiasts of tools and workflows in the domain of distributed data. It is organized by the people behind the git-annex and DataLad projects. The event will comprise a two-day conference and an additional hackathon day.</description></item><item><title>Live Stream</title><link>https://distribits.live/livestream/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://distribits.live/livestream/</guid><description>Watch the conference online Join us virtually in two live streams on April 4th and April 5th via the DataLad YouTube Channel!
Live stream of conference day 1: Take me there Live stream of conference day 2: Take me there During and after a talk, you can ask questions via the Distribits meeting Q&amp;amp;A Matrix Room. The link to this room has been sent to all attendees via email. Keep in mind that the live stream is part of the conference, and thus covered by the Code of Conduct.</description></item><item><title>Location</title><link>https://distribits.live/location/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://distribits.live/location/</guid><description>Venue The event will take place at Haus der Universität in Düsseldorf, Germany.
Location Haus der Universität Düsseldorf
Schadowplatz 14
40212 Düsseldorf View Larger Map Accessibility The venue is in-principle equipped with handicapped accessible facilities. The main entrance stair lift, however, is currently broken. Please refer to the official website for updates. If you require a stair lift, please contact distribits-org@fz-juelich.de.
A separate room is available for nursing or prayer.</description></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>https://distribits.live/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://distribits.live/schedule/</guid><description>At a glance Conference Thursday, 4 April 2024, 9&amp;ndash;17 Friday, 5 April 2024, 9&amp;ndash;17 Hackathon Saturday, 6 April 2024, 9&amp;ndash;17 Event schedule You can also access the schedule information seen below as Pentabarf XML.
For viewing the schedule on mobile, we recommend the Giggity app (F-Droid, Google Play) &amp;ndash; enter the link to the XML file inside the app.
2024-04-04 Arrival and registration 08:30 (00:30) Foyer Welcome and overview 09:00 (00:30) Event Hall Abstract Welcome from the organizers</description></item><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>https://distribits.live/code-of-conduct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://distribits.live/code-of-conduct/</guid><description>Our Pledge We as members, contributors, and leaders pledge to make participation in our community a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of age, body size, visible or invisible disability, ethnicity, sex characteristics, gender identity and expression, level of experience, education, socio-economic status, nationality, personal appearance, race, caste, color, religion, or sexual identity and orientation.
We pledge to act and interact in ways that contribute to an open, welcoming, diverse, inclusive, and healthy community.</description></item><item><title>Thanks!</title><link>https://distribits.live/thanks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://distribits.live/thanks/</guid><description>This meeting is a collaborative effort. It would not have been possible to make it happen without the support of the following individuals and organizations:
The developers and community members of the git-annex and DataLad projects
Heinrich-Heine-Universität Düsseldorf and the staff of the Haus der Universität
Leadership and staff at the Institute of Neurosciences and Medicine (Brain and Behaviour INM-7) at the Helmholtz Research Center Jülich and the Institute of Systems Neuroscience at Heinrich-Heine-Universität Düsseldorf</description></item><item><title>See you soon!</title><link>https://distribits.live/news/see-you-soon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://distribits.live/news/see-you-soon/</guid><description>The meeting is now only a few more weeks away. All attendees and speakers have been confirmed. The list of contributed talks is close to final, and promises an interesting meeting with a broad range of topics.
If you are attending and haven&amp;rsquo;t yet made your travel and accommodation arrangements, we advise to do so as soon as possible, since Düsseldorf is a popular destination for events and tourists and can fill up well in advance.</description></item><item><title>distribits meeting moved to 4-6 April, 2024</title><link>https://distribits.live/news/new-dates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://distribits.live/news/new-dates/</guid><description>After careful consideration, we have decided to move the meeting earlier by two weeks. The new meeting dates are Apr 4-6 2024.
This move was necessary due to a large trade fair in Düsseldorf on the original dates. Hotel and apartment availability is already extremely limited, and for many prohibitively expensive. We gauged the community&amp;rsquo;s feeling before making this decision, and the majority of speakers and attendees responded favorably to the move, although we do recognize the challenges that this causes for some.</description></item><item><title>Notifications sent and Late Registration opens</title><link>https://distribits.live/news/notifications-sent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://distribits.live/news/notifications-sent/</guid><description>We have sent out notifications by email to all who submitted conference and hackathon submissions. However, if you missed the registration deadline, don&amp;rsquo;t worry! It is now possible to submit a late registration and add yourself to the hackathon waiting list.
We plan to accept conference registrations until we reach the venue capacity. We will assess late registrations at an interval of ~ 2 weeks and will send out notification emails.</description></item><item><title>Registration is closed</title><link>https://distribits.live/news/registration-closed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://distribits.live/news/registration-closed/</guid><description>Thanks for everyone&amp;rsquo;s registrations and contribution submissions! It looks like the first distribits meeting is going to be what we hoped for: An inspiring event for technology enthusiasts with many backgrounds. We received registrations from Europe, North America, and Asia, from people working on research data curation, climate science, imaging, archeology, data portals, archiving solutions, small and scale large.
We will now work on finalizing the schedule, and send out emails to everyone by November 1st.</description></item><item><title>Registration closes October 22nd!</title><link>https://distribits.live/news/registration-closes-soon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://distribits.live/news/registration-closes-soon/</guid><description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet, register for the event and hackathon via out online submission/registration system and tell your friends about it. We look forward to meeting you!</description></item></channel></rss>